I'm leaving.
나는 떠난다.
OK.
좋아요.
Don't forget to feed Oscar.
오스카에게 먹이를 주는 것을 잊지 마세요.
Have fun while I'm gone.
내가 없는 동안 재미있게 보내세요.
Why is Oscar so calm?
오스카는 왜 이렇게 침착한 걸까요?
Will he be hungry?
배가 고프겠죠?
Why not...
왜 안돼...
Did you feed Oscar?
오스카에게 밥을 주었나요?
I dislike that woman.
나는 그 여자를 싫어한다.
Dad,
아빠,
Can you end the relationship with her?
그 사람과의 관계를 끝낼 수 있나요?
If you don't...
그렇지 않으면...
Should I go back to mom?
엄마한테 다시 가야 하나?
Before I felt tired but satisfied when I finished working,
피곤해지기 전에 하지만 일을 마치고 나면 만족스러워요.
now you have to be very careful with the director.
이제 아주 조심해야 해 감독과 함께.
How uncomfortable.
얼마나 불편한가.
It's true, we have fewer pregnant women.
사실입니다. 임산부가 적습니다.
I like this silence.
나는 이 침묵을 좋아한다.
this silence
이 침묵
could mean less staff.
직원이 적다는 뜻일 수도 있다.
They could do without us.
우리 없이도 그들은 할 수 있습니다.
We are discouraged, but with energy to spare,
우리는 낙담했지만, 에너지를 아끼지 않고,
Shall we have dinner together?
우리 같이 저녁 먹을까?
- Good idea. - Yes, let's go.
- 좋은 생각이에요. - 응, 가자.
I sign up.
나는 가입한다.
- Where to? - I want guts.
- 어디로요? - 용기를 갖고 싶어요.
Me, lamb skewers.
나, 양꼬치.
- How many rounds? - Hello, Do Hyun.
- 몇 라운드요? - 안녕하세요, 도현님.
- At least three rounds. - Of course.
- 최소 3라운드. - 물론.
- The first, skewers. - Tripe and skewers.
- 첫 번째, 꼬치. - 삼겹살과 꼬치.
I'm about to leave work.
이제 퇴근하려고 해요.
Do Hyun, are you drunk? At this time?
도현아, 취했어? 이때?
We're going to have a lot of fun.
우리는 많은 즐거움을 누릴 것입니다.
Do Hyun.
도현.
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Do you want to walk a little?
조금 걸어볼까?
Daniel told me he was fine.
다니엘은 괜찮다고 말했어요.
It was what he always told me...
그 사람이 항상 나한테 했던 말인데..
which was fine.
괜찮았어요.
I...
나는...
It is obvious that there is no way
방법이 없는 게 분명해
that it was okay.
괜찮았다고.
But, the truth is, I didn't know.
그런데 사실은 몰랐어요.
Of course you didn't know.
물론 당신은 몰랐습니다.
How to know?
어떻게 알 수 있나요?
They hide it at all costs,
그들은 무슨 수를 써서라도 그것을 숨기고,
They don't say a word.
그들은 한마디도하지 않습니다.
I...
나는...
I want to get along with Daniel.
나는 다니엘과 친해지고 싶다.
That?
저것?
Do you think it won't be possible?
불가능할 것이라고 생각하시나요?
No...
아니...
I...
나는...
Honestly, I don't know what to do.
솔직히 어떻게 해야할지 모르겠습니다.
I will do it.
나는 그것을 할 것이다.
Daniel has his times.
다니엘에게는 시간이 있습니다.
I don't know when or how it will be,
언제, 어떻게 될지는 모르겠지만,
but I will look for the opportunity.
하지만 나는 기회를 찾을 것이다.
Who knows? It could be sooner than we expect.
누가 알겠어요? 우리가 예상하는 것보다 더 빠를 수도 있습니다.
Seriously...
진심으로...
I didn't expect
나는 기대하지 않았다
that you said that
네가 그렇게 말했잖아
Daniel's feelings...
다니엘의 감정..
I can't do anything
난 아무것도 할 수 없어
about it
그것에 대해
and I know it will be difficult for you.
그리고 나는 그것이 당신에게 어려울 것임을 압니다.
I can't stop thinking about how you could leave me.
당신이 어떻게 나를 떠날 수 있는지 생각하는 것을 멈출 수 없습니다.
What if you abandon me because of this?
이 때문에 나를 버리면 어떡하지?
You are quite an artist.
당신은 꽤 예술가입니다.
Oh really.
오, 진짜.
[Catholic Church]
[가톨릭교회]
Two adults without commitments
약속 없는 어른 두 명
They spent the night together.
그들은 함께 밤을 보냈습니다.
It was with the consent of both.
두 사람의 동의 하에 이루어진 일이었습니다.
What is the problem?
문제는 무엇입니까?
The truth...
진실은...
It's not a problem.
문제가 되지 않습니다.
Was it a one-time affair?
일회성 사건이었나요?
No!
아니요!
- It wasn't an adventure. - So, it must be love.
- 모험이 아니었어요. - 그럼 사랑이겠죠.
Well,
글쎄,
It's not exactly love either.
그것도 꼭 사랑은 아니다.
So...
그래서...
what is it that torments you
당신을 괴롭히는 것이 무엇입니까?
at this moment?
지금 이 순간?
We've known each other since kindergarten.
우리는 유치원 때부터 서로를 알고 있었어요.
AND?
그리고?
Well...
음...
if this doesn't work,
이것이 작동하지 않으면
I'm afraid it will ruin
망할까봐
a friendship of 20 years.
20년 우정.
So what if it turns out like this?
그렇다면 이렇게 되면 어떨까요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I asked you what's wrong if a 20 year friendship ends.
무슨 일이냐고 물었더니 20년 우정이 끝난다면.
Well...
음...
[Faithful]
[충실한]
Busy.
바빠요.
Hey,
안녕,
Get out of here.
여기서 나가세요.
That?
저것?
I told you to get out.
나가라고 했어요.
Aren't you old enough to be beaten like that?
그렇게 때릴 나이는 아니지 않나?
They didn't hit me, father.
저들은 저를 때리지 않았어요, 아버지.
It was an act of punishment and revenge.
그것은 처벌이자 복수의 행위였습니다.
My God.
맙소사.
Like wood, like wood, they are equal.
나무처럼 나무처럼 그들은 평등합니다.
That?
저것?
Call me "dude," like old times.
옛날처럼 "친구"라고 불러주세요.
Okay, friend.
알았어, 친구.
So,
그래서,
You are between love and friendship, right?
당신은 사랑과 우정 사이에 있는 거죠, 그렇죠?
The same old cliché.
똑같은 진부한 표현.
I don't think it comes down to that, but...
그 정도까지는 아닌 것 같지만...
Do you know what happened between Jun Kyung and me?
준경이랑 나 사이에 무슨 일이 있었는지 알아?
at school, right?
학교에서요?
You call that a relationship?
그걸 관계라고 부르나요?
In any case,
어쨌든,
He didn't like you.
그 사람은 당신을 좋아하지 않았어요.
You harassed her and spread rumors,
당신은 그녀를 괴롭히고 소문을 퍼뜨렸습니다.
In the end my mom threw water on you.
결국 엄마가 너한테 물을 뿌렸어.
I was at my best, full of energy,
나는 최선을 다했고 에너지가 넘쳤습니다.
why did I give up on Jun Kyung instead of enduring that humiliation?
나는 왜 준경을 포기한 걸까? 그 굴욕을 견디는 대신?
That?
저것?
I chose friendship then.
그때 나는 우정을 선택했다.
It was between love and friendship.
사랑과 우정 사이였습니다.
I did it for the sake of a great friendship.
나는 큰 우정을 위해 그렇게했습니다.
Hey.
여기요.
- You were never his type. - Be quiet.
- 당신은 그 사람 타입이 아니었어요. - 조용히 하세요.
Friendship, yes, of course.
물론 우정이죠.
You just lacked courage and confidence,
용기와 자신감이 부족했을 뿐입니다.
Yours is nothing more than a loser's excuse.
당신의 변명은 패자의 변명에 지나지 않습니다.
Do you really not like it?
정말 마음에 안 드시나요?
If you don't like it, why do you care?
마음에 들지 않는다면 왜 신경쓰나요?
It doesn't have a single scratch.
흠집 하나도 없습니다.
What an idiot.
정말 바보입니다.
Listen.
듣다.
It's sudden,
갑자기,
but our publicist, Hwang Beom Jun,
그런데 저희 홍보 담당자 황범준님이
He just handed in his resignation.
그는 방금 사직서를 제출했습니다.
He feels guilty, so tonight he invites.
그는 죄책감을 느끼고, 그래서 오늘 밤 그는 초대합니다.
Let's all go out after work.
퇴근하고 다들 나가자.
Let's make him spend a lot of money before he leaves.
그 사람이 떠나기 전에 많은 돈을 쓰게 해보자.
He said he would treat us to the most expensive!
그는 우리를 가장 비싼 대접하겠다고 말했습니다!
See you! I invite you to dinner!
또 봐요! 나는 당신을 저녁 식사에 초대합니다!
It's great,
훌륭해요
you give up for love, You go to Europe and you don't know when you'll come back.
당신은 사랑을 포기하고, 유럽에 가더라도 언제 돌아올지 알 수 없습니다.
I wish I was your age, Beom Jun.
나도 범준이네 나이였으면 좋겠다.
You still have time,
아직 시간이 있으니,
boss.
보스.
I don't have the courage or the talent.
용기도 없고 재능도 없어요.
It's not about talent,
재능에 관한 것이 아니라,
only people who work for fun can do it.
오직 재미를 위해 일하는 사람들 할 수 있습니다.
Where in Europe will you go?
유럽 ​​어디로 갈까?
He said he wants to visit Estonia,
그는 에스토니아를 방문하고 싶다고 말했습니다.
so we will start with the Baltic States.
발트해 연안 국가부터 시작하겠습니다.
The Baltic States.
발트해 연안 국가.
I've only heard about them in books.
나는 그들에 대해 책에서만 들어봤습니다.
Where are the Baltic States?
발트해 연안 국가는 어디에 있습니까?
- Are you leaving? - Are you leaving already?
- 떠나는 거야? - 벌써 떠나시나요?
I think so.
그렇게 생각해요.
I tell you it's not that.
나는 그것이 아니라고 말씀드립니다.
Enough.
충분한.
- I'm sick of hearing that. - A cake!
- 그 말을 들으니 마음이 아프네요. - 케이크!
That?
저것?
See? That's the spirit.
보다? 그것이 바로 정신입니다.
After all, it's a farewell party.
결국 송별회네요.
- Oh really? - Did you go get a cake?
- 오, 진짜? - 케이크 사러 갔어?
Congratulations.
축하해요.
Have a nice trip to Europe with your girlfriend.
유럽여행 잘 다녀오세요 여자친구랑.
Thank you...
감사합니다...
True...
사실...
you are only faithful to your feelings, I'm the idiot.
당신은 자신의 감정에만 충실하고, 나는 바보입니다.
No!
아니요!
- That?
- 저것?
- What was that? - What's happening?
- 그게 뭐였죠? - 무슨 일이에요?
Why did he do that?
왜 그랬나요?
For Mrs. Oh Mi Ja's 80th birthday.
오미자 여사님의 80번째 생일을 맞이하여.
Understood.
이해했다.
I'm not that stingy.
나는 그렇게 인색하지 않습니다.
If you order more than 300 towels, I include everything at no additional cost.
수건 300개 이상 주문 시, 추가 비용 없이 모든 것을 포함합니다.
Keep your voice down, I'm talking on the phone.
목소리를 낮추세요. 통화 중이에요.
No! Yes, go ahead.
아니요! 예, 계속하세요.
Good.
좋은.
We will do it for you. Fine, thanks.
우리는 당신을 위해 그것을 할 것입니다. 좋아요, 고마워요.
-Jin Ho! - That?
-진호! - 저것?
You didn't say you were coming. What brings you here?
당신은 온다고 말하지 않았습니다. 무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
You got my message, right?
내 메시지 받았지, 그렇지?
Yes.
예.
Grey, pink and white, a hundred of each.
회색, 분홍색, 흰색, 각각 100개씩.
Yes, have them ready for the 15th.
네, 15일까지 준비하세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Please understand her.
그녀를 이해해주세요.
You know how it is.
당신은 그것이 어떤지 알고 있습니다.
What's wrong with him?
그 사람에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
It's the best.
최고입니다.
Did all the good people die?
좋은 사람들은 다 죽었나요?
I'm not asking it to be soft like a new towel.
새 수건처럼 부드러워지길 바라는 게 아닙니다.
However,
그러나,
it shouldn't be rough
거칠면 안 돼
like a dish towel.
행주처럼.
What scrubbing towel?
무슨 수세미?
You scared me.
당신은 나를 겁주었어요.
When did you arrive?
언제 도착하셨나요?
And the store?
그리고 가게는?
It's empty. You stay, hurry up.
비어 있습니다. 넌 있어, 서둘러.
That?
저것?
OK.
좋아요.
I'll come visit you soon.
곧 방문하겠습니다.
When he brought you home to announce that they would get married,
그 사람이 당신을 집에 데려왔을 때 결혼한다는 소식을 전하기 위해
Everyone opposed it, it was chaos.
모두가 반대했고 혼란스러웠습니다.
- It must have been like that. - Yes.
- 그랬나봐요. - 예.
Remember how old they were back then.
그 당시 그들이 몇 살이었는지 기억해 보세요.
But do you know that I was the only one
그런데 나만 그랬다는 걸 아시나요?
who approved it?
누가 승인했어?
Of course, I know.
물론이죠.
My sister asked me why I supported them.
언니는 나에게 왜 그들을 지지하는지 물었습니다.
Do you know what I answered?
내가 뭐라고 대답했는지 아세요?
I told him you were vulgar, so other girls wouldn't like you.
나는 그에게 당신이 저속하다고 말했습니다. 그러면 다른 여자들이 당신을 좋아하지 않을 거예요.
That is,
즉,
You couldn't cheat on her with anyone.
누구와도 그녀를 속일 수는 없었습니다.
I don't know what to say in this situation,
이 상황에서는 무슨 말을 해야 할지 모르겠는데,
but, seriously,
하지만 진지하게,
- it's a misunderstanding. - No.
- 오해예요. - 아니.
You didn't have the guts
넌 배짱이 없었어
to deceive my sister while she was alive.
내 여동생이 살아 있는 동안 속이기 위해서였다.
How could I not know?
내가 어떻게 모를 수 있겠는가?
My husband does nothing but laugh
남편은 웃기만 하고 아무것도 안 해요
when clients don't pay you.
고객이 돈을 지불하지 않을 때.
I've seen him do that for over 20 years.
나는 그가 그렇게 하는 것을 20년 넘게 보아왔습니다.
Maybe I'm selfish
어쩌면 난 이기적인지도 몰라
But I see my husband and my blood boils.
그런데 남편을 보니 피가 끓어오르네요.
Yes...
응...
he would have had an accident and it would have ended like this...
그 사람은 사고를 당했을 거야 그러면 이렇게 끝났을텐데...
If I had to change his diapers for seven years
만약 내가 그의 기저귀를 갈아주어야 한다면 7년 동안
and I would have had to endure that temper,
그리고 나는 그 성질을 참아야 했을 것이다.
no way
절대 안돼
I could have done it.
나는 그것을 할 수 있었다.
But he probably did,
하지만 그는 아마 그랬을 겁니다.
because he is a fool.
그는 바보이기 때문입니다.
Although we are family,
우리는 가족이지만,
I only thought about my poor sister.
나는 불쌍한 여동생 생각만 했어요.
I didn't think about how difficult...
어렵다고 생각 안했는데..
that was for you.
그것은 당신을 위한 것이었습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
No, it's okay.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
I still can't congratulate you on that woman.
나는 아직도 그 여자를 축하할 수 없습니다.
I won't do it until the day I die.
죽는 날까지 안 할 거예요.
But thanks
하지만 고마워요
for taking care of my sister.
내 여동생을 돌봐줘서.
Thank you so much.
매우 감사합니다.
- May you get home safely. - Bye bye.
- 집에 무사히 돌아가길 바랍니다. - 안녕.
Stop babbling.
옹알이는 그만하세요.
- Is it fun? - Yes, it's fun!
- 재미있나요? - 네, 재미있어요!
Let's go for the second round!
두 번째 라운드로 가자!
Why do I always find you sitting here?
왜 나는 항상 당신이 여기 앉아 있는 것을 발견합니까?
Don't you have anywhere else to go?
더 갈 곳은 없나요?
Don't you respect my house?
우리 집을 존중하지 않나요?
Why...
왜...
are you so irritable?
너 그렇게 짜증나?
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
What happened to your face?
얼굴에 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
I asked you what you are doing here.
여기서 뭐 하시는지 물었습니다.
I thought I should apologize.
사과해야겠다고 생각했어요.
Apologize for what?
무엇에 대해 사과하나요?
I just broke up
방금 헤어졌어
with Sun...
썬과 함께...
- and... - Forget it.
-그리고... - 잊어버려요.
My feelings belong to me.
내 감정은 나에게 속한다.
I don't expect anything from you.
나는 당신에게 아무것도 기대하지 않습니다.
You don't have to say anything else.
다른 말을 할 필요가 없습니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Well,
글쎄,
there is something else.
다른 것이 있습니다.
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
-Whatever I can do... - Tell them.
- 내가 할 수 있는 건 뭐든지... - 그들에게 말해주세요.
Tell them you will do the internship.
인턴십을 할 것이라고 말하세요.
- That? - You were sorry.
- 저것? - 미안했어요.
You didn't do anything before your mother died.
당신은 어머니가 돌아가시기 전에 아무것도 하지 않으셨습니다.
You know I had something to do with that, right?
내가 그 일과 관련이 있다는 걸 아시죠?
So take back the chance
그러니 기회를 다시 잡아라
and invite me to eat accordingly.
그에 따라 식사하도록 초대하십시오.
Anything else.
다른 것.
Stop doubting everything.
모든 것을 의심하지 마세요.
There are those who quit their jobs and they are proud of it.
직장을 그만둔 사람도 있고 그리고 그들은 그것을 자랑스러워합니다.
They break up because they feel like it and go to Europe.
그들은 마음이 편해서 헤어지고 유럽으로 갑니다.
Look at us.
우리를보세요.
Why are we so idiots?
우리는 왜 그렇게 바보입니까?
Good heavens!
맙소사!
You don't know how happy I am...
내가 얼마나 행복한지 모르실 겁니다...
that you have come...
당신이 왔다고...
to see me.
나를 만나러
Daniel!
다니엘!
I came because I have something to tell you.
드릴 말씀이 있어서 왔습니다.
No!
아니요!
Child!
어린이!
Watch where you're going!
어디로 가는지 조심하세요!
What are you doing? He fell and hurt himself.
뭐하세요? 그는 넘어져 다쳤습니다.
I didn't hit him.
나는 그를 때리지 않았다.
He fell alone.
그는 혼자 넘어졌습니다.
You said it, it's a boy.
말했잖아, 남자애야.
You should have asked him if he was okay.
그 사람이 괜찮은지 물어봤어야 했는데.
Cars pass by here,
여기도 차들이 지나가고,
I shouldn't be doing that.
나는 그런 일을 해서는 안 된다.
Who are you?
누구세요?
Are you his mother?
당신은 그의 어머니인가요?
Yes.
예.
I am your mother.
나는 당신의 어머니입니다.
Let me see.
어디 보자.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
For saying you're my mother?
당신이 내 엄마라고 해서요?
No.
아니요.
For not asking you first
먼저 묻지 않아서
whether you were good or bad.
당신이 좋은지 나쁜지.
I had many opportunities to do it.
나는 그것을 할 기회가 많았습니다.
I asked dad
아빠한테 물어봤는데
to stop going out with you.
너랑 그만 나가려고.
I'm...
나는...
regretful
유감스럽다
Because?
왜냐면?
I dislike you,
나는 당신이 싫어요
but I don't want dad to be sad.
하지만 나는 아빠가 슬퍼하는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
You don't like me either, right?
너도 날 좋아하지 않지?
Who likes someone who hates them?
자신을 미워하는 사람을 누가 좋아합니까?
Hurts.
아파요.
Use protective equipment from now on.
지금부터 보호 장비를 사용하십시오.
Well,
글쎄,
That makes me look like a fool.
그게 나를 바보처럼 보이게 해요.
I'm hungry.
배고파요.
Shall we eat?
우리 먹을까요?
Is it spicy?
매워요?
I want to get used to it.
나는 그것에 익숙해지고 싶다.
If you find it spicy, don't eat it. Why do you do it?
매운 것 같으면 먹지 마세요. 왜 그러는 걸까요?
Because I want to get along
왜냐면 난 어울리고 싶거든
with the people.
사람들과 함께.
Can I ask you something?
뭐 좀 물어봐도 될까요?
Why did you name him Oscar?
왜 그 사람 이름을 오스카라고 지었나요?
I mean the fish.
내 말은 물고기를 의미합니다.
Do I have to...
꼭 해야 하나...
tell you?
말해봐?
It's the name...
이름이에요...
of a boy
소년의
that bothered me in Germany.
그것이 독일에서 나를 괴롭혔다.
He was the boy I hated the most.
그 사람은 내가 가장 싫어하는 아이였다.
Clear.
분명한.
I see.
알겠어요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I'll change the name.
이름을 바꾸겠습니다.
No.
아니요.
I like that name.
나는 그 이름을 좋아한다.
Is it better now?
이제 나아졌나요?
Did the milk help?
우유가 도움이 됐나요?
I hadn't tried it, but it's very good.
해보지는 않았지만 매우 좋습니다.
Is it the first time?
처음인가요?
Didn't he ever buy it for you?
그 사람이 당신을 위해 그것을 사준 적도 없나요?
It's very good, eat it.
아주 맛있어요, 먹어보세요.
It's delicious.
맛있어요.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
You only serve the guide.
당신은 가이드만을 섬깁니다.
It is the dictatorship of the one who has the tweezers.
핀셋 가진 자의 독재다.
I am not a dictator.
나는 독재자가 아니다.
Don't give me so much,
너무 많이 주지 마세요.
Eat too, Jin Ho.
너도 먹어, 진호.
That?
저것?
- Eat. - What's wrong with you two?
- 먹다. - 너희 둘에게 무슨 문제가 있는 거야?
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
The way they look at each other is suspicious.
서로를 바라보는 눈빛이 의심스럽다.
One moment,
잠시만요,
Are you dating the guide?
가이드랑 데이트 중이신가요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
He doesn't deny it.
그는 그것을 부정하지 않습니다.
It just can't be!
그럴 리가 없어!
That?
저것?
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
- That?
- 저것?
Yes, we are dating.
네, 우리 데이트해요
Why don't you sing a song?
노래를 불러보는 게 어때요?
I sing very badly, you better do it.
나는 노래를 아주 나쁘게 부릅니다. 당신이하는 것이 좋습니다.
Do you think you're at a concert?
콘서트에 온 것 같나요?
You pay the entrance or you sing. You choose!
입장료를 지불하거나 노래를 부릅니다. 선택하세요!
- No. - Choose.
- 아니. - 선택하세요.
Sing a song.
노래를 불러보세요.
It's my turn, I'm going to sing.
내 차례야, 내가 노래할게.
Today you are very happy.
오늘 당신은 매우 행복합니다.
Yes, I am.
네, 그렇습니다.
Excellent.
훌륭한.
We only took one trip together,
딱 한 번만 같이 여행을 갔는데,
but we keep meeting,
그런데 우리는 계속 만나요.
We have fun and we support each other.
우리는 즐겁고 서로를 지지합니다.
The reason I'm so happy
내가 너무 행복한 이유
It's that we don't hide our relationship.
우리의 관계를 숨기지 않는다는 것입니다.
we don't worry because of what others would think.
우리는 걱정하지 않아요 다른 사람들이 어떻게 생각할지 때문입니다.
I agree.
동의합니다.
Ja Yeong...
자영...
I have to ask you a favor.
부탁이 하나 있습니다.
If you do me a favor first,
먼저 나한테 부탁을 하면
I will listen to you.
나는 당신의 말을 듣습니다.
OK.
좋아요.
Tell me and I will do it.
나에게 말하면 내가 할 것이다.
Sing me a song.
나에게 노래를 불러주세요.
That?
저것?
Impossible,
불가능하다,
I sing very badly.
나는 노래를 아주 나쁘게 부른다.
I won't do you the favor.
나는 당신에게 호의를 베풀지 않을 것입니다.
Come on, it's not fair.
어서, 이건 불공평해요.
What if I take you on a horseback ride?
내가 당신을 말 타고 데려가면 어떨까요?
No.
아니요.
I sing very badly.
나는 노래를 아주 나쁘게 부른다.
Okay, but don't laugh.
알았어, 하지만 웃지 마.
Now?
지금?
Here?
여기?
When and where else should I do it?
언제, 어디서 또 해야 하나요?
Don't laugh.
웃지 마세요.
Promise me.
약속해요.
♪ Stay ♪
♪ 머물다 ♪
Don't laugh.
웃지 마세요.
♪ By my side ♪
♪ 내 곁에 ♪
♪ Don't go ♪
♪ 가지 마세요 ♪
♪ Don't do it ♪
♪ 하지 마세요 ♪
♪ Longing is left behind ♪
♪ 그리움은 남겨두고 ♪
♪ On the long road ♪
♪ 긴 여정 속에서 ♪
♪ You can't go back ♪
♪ 넌 돌아갈 수 없어 ♪
♪ In search of the rainbow ♪
♪ 무지개를 찾아서 ♪
♪ The cold wind ♪
♪ 차가운 바람 ♪
♪ Blow ♪
♪ 불어 ♪
♪ You cry alone ♪
♪ 혼자 울어요 ♪
♪ But I will always be ♪
♪ 하지만 난 언제나 그럴 거예요 ♪
♪ By your side ♪
♪ 당신 곁에 ♪
♪ I will never leave you ♪
♪ 난 결코 당신을 떠나지 않을 거예요 ♪
I sing badly, right?
내가 노래를 잘 못 부르죠?
No,
아니요,
I loved it.
나는 그것을 좋아했다.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
Now tell me,
이제 말해 보세요.
I will grant you that favor.
그 은혜를 베풀겠습니다.
Well,
글쎄,
Ja Yeong.
자영.
You will see...
당신은 볼 것이다 ...
Dinner with your family?
가족과 함께 저녁 식사를 하시나요?
If that seems too much to you, we can wait a little longer.
그게 너무 과해 보인다면, 우리는 조금 더 기다릴 수 있습니다.
Why would it seem like too much?
왜 너무 많은 것처럼 보일까요?
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
So, bring Daniel.
그러니 다니엘을 데려오세요.
I told Dad and Jun Seo about Daniel.
나는 아빠와 준서에게 다니엘에 대해 말했다.
As long as Daniel wants to do it,
다니엘이 하고 싶어하는 한,
We can all get together.
우리는 모두 함께 모일 수 있습니다.
Thanks for bringing me home.
집에 데려다줘서 고마워요.
I should thank you today.
오늘은 감사해야겠습니다.
Will you thank me and nothing more? Don't you forget something?
나에게 감사하고 더 이상은 없습니까? 뭔가 잊지 않았나요?
Dad?
아빠?
Yes.
예.
Good evening, nice to meet you.
좋은 저녁입니다. 만나서 반가워요.
Yes, hello.
네, 안녕하세요.
Dad.
아빠.
Yes.
예.
You should have called before coming.
오기 전에 전화했어야지.
I had a meeting nearby
근처에서 회의가 있었어요
and I passed by here.
그리고 나는 여기를 지나갔다.
He is very handsome.
그는 매우 잘생겼다.
- Yes. - Made a good impression.
- 예. - 좋은 인상을 남겼어요.
Yes.
예.
- Take napkins. - Thank you.
- 냅킨을 가져가세요. - 감사합니다.
I open it.
나는 그것을 연다.
He seems like a good guy.
그는 좋은 사람인 것 같습니다.
Yes it is.
그렇습니다.
- Would you like...?
- 원하시나요...?
You first.
당신이 먼저.
No, you first.
아니, 당신이 먼저요.
Okay, me first.
알았어, 나 먼저.
Would you like us to have dinner with Ja Yeong? one of these days?
자영이랑 저녁 먹을래? 요즘 어느 날?
Is it too soon?
너무 이르지 않나요?
I don't want to pressure you. It's just that...
나는 당신에게 압력을 가하고 싶지 않습니다. 단지 그게...
I would love to.
나는하고 싶습니다.
Let's have dinner.
저녁을 먹자.
Are you sure?
확실합니까?
- Come in. - Yes.
- 들어오세요. - 네.
Hey.
여기요.
That?
저것?
It doesn't matter, come in.
상관없어요, 들어오세요.
- Dad... - Come in.
- 아빠... - 들어오세요.
- Well, hope you get home safely. - Thank you.
- 그럼 집에 무사히 돌아가길 바랍니다. - 감사합니다.
This is a story of the Night Listener.
이것은 Night Listener의 이야기입니다.
"When I worked at dawn in a store,
"새벽에 가게에서 일할 때
a client always came
고객이 항상 왔습니다
at the same time
동시에
and with the same clothes to buy the same beer."
그리고 같은 옷을 입고 같은 맥주를 사려고요."
What?
무엇?
"He never spoke
"그는 결코 말을 하지 않았습니다
nor did he show any emotion.
그는 아무런 감정도 나타내지 않았습니다.
When I looked at her,
내가 그녀를 보았을 때
I felt like I saw myself reflected in a mirror.
거울에 비친 내 모습을 본 것 같은 느낌이 들었습니다.
I think the early morning is like that,
이른 아침은 그런 것 같아요,
it is a moment when you cannot hide anything.
아무것도 숨길 수 없는 순간입니다.
During the day, We pretend to be happy or not feel alone.
낮에는 우리는 행복한 척하거나 외롭지 않은 척합니다.
We can hide somewhere in between
우리는 그 사이 어딘가에 숨을 수 있습니다
between happiness and loneliness.
행복과 외로움 사이
But it is not possible to do it at dawn.
단, 새벽에는 불가능합니다.
It is the moment when you know for sure
확실히 알게 되는 순간
that you are not at that intermediate point.
당신은 그 중간 지점에 있지 않습니다.
- He didn't ask anything." - He didn't ask anything.
- 그는 아무 것도 묻지 않았어요." - 그는 아무것도 묻지 않았습니다.
- "He didn't say anything." - He didn't say anything.
- "그는 아무 말도 하지 않았어요." - 그는 아무 말도 하지 않았습니다.
His presence was comforting.
그의 존재는 위안이 되었습니다.
She stayed with me.
그녀는 나와 함께 있었습니다.
Seeing her so similar to me, I wanted to thank you...
그녀가 나와 너무 비슷한 걸 보니, 감사드리고 싶었어요...
but I couldn't.
하지만 그럴 수 없었습니다.
He never bought beer again.
그는 다시는 맥주를 사지 않았습니다.
I felt great relief.
큰 안도감을 느꼈습니다.
Surely, she doesn't feel so alone anymore.
확실히 그녀는 더 이상 외롭다고 느끼지 않습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
If we meet again,
우리 다시 만난다면
I'll buy you a beer.
맥주 사드릴게요
Didn't you say you didn't need anything?
아무것도 필요없다고 하지 않았나요?
Yes.
예.
I said that.
나는 그렇게 말했다.
That was just a week ago, just one week.
불과 일주일 전의 일이었는데, 딱 일주일.
Are you suddenly going to do it now?
지금 갑자기 그러려고 하는 거야?
I thought I didn't need anything,
아무것도 필요없다고 생각했는데,
But I realized something important.
그런데 중요한 사실을 깨달았습니다.
I saw you too sensitive for a career in science and engineering.
네가 너무 예민한 걸 봤어 과학 및 공학 분야의 경력을 위해.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Isn't it embarrassing
부끄럽지 않은가
retract like this?
이렇게 철회해?
It's shameful,
부끄럽다,
yes.
응.
Should I consider this effort?
이런 노력을 고려해야 할까요?
It is very difficult to be fair.
공정하게 행동하는 것은 매우 어렵습니다.
Excuse me,
실례합니다.
And Professor Park's announcement?
그리고 박교수의 발표는?
- I sent it to print a while ago. - Good.
- 얼마전에 인쇄해서 보냈어요. - 좋은.
- Marketing. - Yes.
- 마케팅. - 예.
Did you check the interview schedule?
면접일정은 확인하셨나요?
I'm on it.
나는 그것에 있습니다.
Hurry up!
서둘러요!
Yeah!
응!
I decided to resume the internship.
인턴십을 재개하기로 결정했습니다.
It was thanks to you then and it's thanks to you now.
그때는 네 덕분이었지 이제 당신 덕분이에요.
Where is the ssamjang?
쌈장은 어디에 있나요?
Here it is.
여기 있습니다.
Raphael!
라파엘!
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Father,
아버지,
How strange to see you here.
여기서 만나다니 정말 이상하네요.
Yes.
예.
We will take the father to visit a new parishioner.
우리는 아버지를 데려갈 것이다 새로운 교구민을 방문하기 위해.
I see.
알겠어요.
How have you been?
잘 지내셨나요?
Thanks to your prayers, I'm fine.
여러분의 기도 덕분에 저는 괜찮습니다.
You look much better.
당신은 훨씬 좋아 보인다.
You must be at peace now.
이제 편히 쉬셔야 합니다.
Yes, thanks to all of you.
네, 모두 감사합니다.
But they say that is not always the case.
그러나 그들은 항상 그런 것은 아니라고 말합니다.
They say that the first year after mourning It is the most dangerous.
애도 후 첫 해가 된다고 하던데 가장 위험합니다.
Let's finish shopping.
쇼핑을 마치자.
I am very worried.
나는 매우 걱정된다.
Father.
아버지.
- We have to go visit Raphael too... -Jin Ho.
- 우리도 라파엘을 만나러 가야 하는데... -진호.
Is it enough?
충분합니까?
And who is she?
그리고 그녀는 누구입니까?
Well...
음...
It's my girlfriend.
내 여자친구야.
Ja Yeong, please say hello.
자영씨, 인사해주세요.
He is the priest of my church,
그 사람은 우리 교회의 목사님이십니다.
the lady I mentioned
내가 언급한 그 여자
and other members.
그리고 다른 회원들.
Please say hello.
인사해주세요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Well, we should finish shopping.
자, 쇼핑을 마무리해야겠습니다.
Yes, go ahead.
예, 계속하세요.
Honey, are we going there?
여보, 우리 거기로 갈까요?
I'm sorry!
죄송합니다!
Alright.
괜찮은.
One, two, three, four.
하나, 둘, 셋, 넷.
They are going to be missing.
그들은 실종될 것입니다.
It smells good.
냄새가 좋아요.
Could you try it?
시도해 볼 수 있나요?
Clear.
분명한.
Be careful, it's hot.
조심하세요. 뜨거워요.
Wait.
기다리다.
Someone must have arrived by now.
지금쯤 누군가 도착했을 것입니다.
You arrived earlier than I expected.
예상보다 일찍 도착하셨어요.
Yes.
예.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Well...
음...
It's...
그것은 ...
Hey...
안녕...
Could you try the soup?
수프를 맛보실 수 있나요?
Clear.
분명한.
How are you doing?
어떻게 지내세요?
For me,
나에게는
It's a little bland.
조금 밋밋해요.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
I think it's okay.
내 생각엔 괜찮은 것 같아.
Yeah?
응?
Is it bland?
그것은 단조로운가?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
- What's happening?
- 무슨 일이에요?
No,
아니요,
I think it is well seasoned.
양념이 잘 된 것 같아요.
Why do they act so natural?
그들은 왜 그렇게 자연스럽게 행동하는 걸까요?
- Shall I let it boil a little more? - No.
- 조금 더 끓여드릴까요? - 아니.
It could be very salty. I think that's fine.
매우 짠맛이 날 수 있습니다. 내 생각엔 괜찮을 것 같아.
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
The fire does not light.
불이 켜지지 않습니다.
I didn't know we had one of those.
나는 우리에게 그런 것이 있는지 몰랐습니다.
No, it's new.
아니요, 새로운 것입니다.
I didn't know if it would be useful,
유용하게 쓰일지 몰랐는데,
but, if I had it, I would end up using it.
하지만 만약 내가 그것을 가지고 있었다면 나는 그것을 사용하게 될 것입니다.
It was a good idea.
좋은 생각이었습니다.
I arrived.
나는 도착했다.
- Hello. - You arrived.
- 안녕하세요. - 도착했어요.
Hello, Bom.
안녕, 봄.
You remember me, don't you?
나를 기억하지?
How have you been?
잘 지내셨나요?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
He's handsome, not like you.
그 사람은 잘생겼는데 너랑은 달라
That?
저것?
I'm not ugly.
나는 못생긴 사람이 아니다.
Look, smoke follows attractive guys.
보세요, 연기는 매력적인 남자를 따릅니다.
I'm coming.
나는 간다.
Go.
가다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Jun Seo.
서준.
- So long. - Yes.
- 오랜만이에요. - 예.
So long.
그럼 또.
- Go ahead, please. - Yes.
- 어서 가세요. - 예.
Come on in, come say hello.
들어와서 인사하세요.
Welcome.
환영.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
You must be Daniel.
당신은 다니엘이 틀림없어요.
You're handsome, like your dad.
당신은 당신의 아버지처럼 잘생겼어요.
- This is for you. - You shouldn't have bothered.
- 이건 당신을 위한 거예요. - 귀찮게 하지 말았어야 했는데.
This way, please.
이쪽으로 부탁드립니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Is this for me?
이게 나한테 맞는 걸까?
How pretty!
정말 예뻐요!
Come in, please, sit down.
들어와서 앉으세요.
- Thanks for the food. - Enjoy it.
- 음식 고마워요. - 즐겨보세요.
He still doesn't know how to put together a ssam.
그는 아직도 쌈을 어떻게 조합하는지 모른다.
You put garlic and peppers on the meat.
고기에 마늘과 고추를 올려줍니다.
- Take. - Come on.
- 가져가다. - 어서 해봐요.
- Dad! - Add one more.
- 아빠! - 하나 더 추가합니다.
Dad!
아빠!
It's spicy, so it cuts the fat. It's delicious, try it.
매콤해서 지방을 빼줍니다. 맛있어요 꼭 드셔보세요
How are you? Delicious, right?
어떻게 지내세요? 맛있죠?
Don't eat it!
먹지 마세요!
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
- It's very spicy. - My God!
- 엄청 매워요. - 맙소사!
- Water, please! - Dad!
- 물 주세요! - 아빠!
[Tonight, the memory of him oppresses her heart]
[오늘 밤, 그에 대한 기억이 그녀의 마음을 짓누른다]
Hey.
안녕.
Oh really?
오, 진짜?
Dad, he can't tolerate spicy food.
아빠, 매운 음식을 못 먹거든요.
No, without a doubt.
아니, 의심할 여지 없이요.
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
Just swallow it. Swallow it.
그냥 삼키세요. 그것을 삼켜라.
Do you want to spit it out?
뱉어내시겠어요?
Look how red his face is.
얼굴이 얼마나 빨개졌는지 보세요.
- I'm going out for a while. - OK.
- 잠시 외출할 예정이에요. - 좋아요.
Let's toast with water.
물로 건배하자.
Health.
건강.
[Delicious Battered Pork]
[맛있는 돼지고기 반죽]
Just pork chop? Isn't it dry?
그냥 돼지갈비? 건조한거 아냐?
A portion of jjolmyeon, please.
쫄면 한 부분 주세요.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
It hurt me...
상처받았어...
not see you for a few days
며칠 동안 보지 못해요
and not being able...
그리고 못해서...
contact you.
당신에게 연락하십시오.
I didn't realize before.
나는 전에는 몰랐습니다.
Actually, I...
사실 나는...
I think I like to cut you the pork chops.
내 생각엔 널 잘라내고 싶은 것 같아 돼지갈비.
Yes.
예.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
I like to take them off the plate and cut them.
나는 접시에서 꺼내서 자르는 것을 좋아합니다.
And I love it...
그리고 나는 그것을 좋아합니다 ...
the noisy way you eat the chop...
네가 찹쌀을 먹는 시끄러운 방식...
that I cut you into pieces.
내가 너를 조각조각 자른 것.
So...
그래서...
So what?
그래서 뭐?
So I invite.
그래서 초대합니다.
Heavens.
천국.
That's all?
그게 다야?
Hey,
안녕,
I'm still studying.
나는 아직 공부 중이에요.
Eat.
먹다.
Open your mouth.
입을 벌려라.
Is it good?
좋은가요?
Yes.
예.
Very good?
매우 좋은?
The summer,
여름
noisier and hotter than usual,
평소보다 더 시끄럽고 더워요
was coming to an end.
끝나고 있었습니다.
Thus the seasons passed,
이렇게 계절이 지나갔고,
and they arrived
그리고 그들은 도착했다
other seasons.
다른 계절
[Test Drive]
[테스트 드라이브]
Some seasons taught me
어떤 계절이 나에게 가르쳐 주었나요
that what he was afraid of
그가 두려워했던 것
it wasn't that big of a deal.
그렇게 큰 일은 아니었습니다.
Vehicle number 15, you passed.
15번 차량이 지나갔습니다.
We go through seasons that gave us the joy of growing
계절을 지나간다 우리에게 성장의 기쁨을 준
and to reflect on our clumsiness.
그리고 우리의 서투름을 반성합니다.
Stations that marked
표시된 역
the end of expected projects and plans.
예상 프로젝트 및 계획의 종료
[Congratulations, future writer!] Surprise!
[축하해요, 미래의 작가님!] 놀랍습니다!
Congratulations on resigning!
퇴사를 축하합니다!
No matter how much we anticipated and we prepared,
아무리 기대해도 우리는 준비했습니다.
there were seasons
계절이 있었습니다
in which sadness was inevitable.
슬픔은 불가피했습니다.
Thank you for coming to me as my daughter.
내 딸로 와주셔서 감사해요.
Thank you
감사합니다
for letting me be your mom.
내가 네 엄마가 되도록 허락해줘서.
Among moments of bitterness,
씁쓸한 순간들 속에서
of consolation,
위로의
of warmth,
따뜻함
with emotion...
감정으로...
and cold...
춥고...
several stations
여러 방송국
they were passing.
그들은 지나가고 있었어요.
Now
지금
another spring
또 다른 봄
blooms.
꽃이 피었습니다.
[Welcome, entrants, to Seongeun University!]
[환영합니다, 참가자 여러분. 성은대학교로!]
Five minutes left.
5분 남았습니다.
Holding on to that means there is no hope.
계속 붙잡고 있으면 희망이 없다는 뜻이다.
Just a few more seconds, please.
몇 초만 더 기다려 주세요.
Clear.
분명한.
Those five minutes
그 5분
They are part of the tuition you earned. with so much effort.
이는 귀하가 벌어들인 수업료의 일부입니다. 정말 많은 노력으로.
Use them.
그것들을 사용하세요.
Hello, teaching assistant.
안녕하세요, 조교님.
So long.
그럼 또.
Yes, it's been a long time.
네, 오랜만이에요.
- Hi teacher. - Hello.
- 안녕하세요 선생님. - 안녕하세요.
What envy.
정말 부러워요.
Look at you, teacher.
선생님 보세요.
Stay close to Professor Song.
송교수님과 친하게 지내세요.
You never know.
당신은 결코 알지 못합니다.
Come on, me?
어서, 나?
Now that you're done, let's go eat something.
이제 다 끝났으니 뭐 먹으러 가자.
Sorry, I have a class, so I must go to Ansan.
미안, 나 수업이 있어. 그래서 안산으로 가야 해요.
Alright.
괜찮은.
Bye bye.
안녕.
I'm pathetic, aren't I?
나는 한심한 사람이지, 그렇지?
Awful.
끔찍한.
Well...
음...
You are very sensitive, it is unusual for you.
당신은 매우 예민해서 당신에게는 이례적인 일입니다.
But you look sexy.
그런데 당신은 섹시해 보여요.
They went out for a long time, The time finally came.
그들은 오랫동안 외출을 했고, 마침내 시간이 왔습니다.
You spent too much time breaking up.
당신은 헤어지는 데 너무 많은 시간을 소비했습니다.
Everyone uses mobile invitations nowadays.
요즘에는 누구나 모바일 초대장을 사용합니다.
They insisted on doing everything for the wedding.
그들은 결혼식을 위해 모든 것을 하겠다고 고집했습니다.
I heard they almost broke up because of that.
그 때문에 거의 헤어질 뻔 했다고 들었어요.
I won't give you the bouquet.
나는 당신에게 꽃다발을 주지 않을 것이다.
I'm going now.
나는 지금 간다.
You didn't forget about next Saturday, right?
다음주 토요일 잊지 않으셨죠?
No, I didn't forget.
아니요, 잊지 않았습니다.
- Leave. - Have a good day.
- 떠나다. - 좋은 하루 보내세요.
Bye bye.
안녕.
I think I'll be late.
늦을 것 같아요.
There is a lot of traffic.
교통량이 많습니다.
And the flowers? Did you get them?
그리고 꽃은요? 당신은 그것을 얻었나요?
Damn! What do I do?
젠장! 어떻게 해야 하나요?
It will take me a long time to find a florist.
꽃집을 찾는 데 시간이 오래 걸릴 것 같아요.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
I'll buy them, you arrive as soon as possible.
내가 사줄게, 너는 최대한 빨리 도착해.
Drive carefully,
조심히 운전하세요,
but hurry up!
하지만 서둘러!
[Daniel, you are the best!]
[다니엘, 네가 최고야!]
Everyone else is already here.
다른 사람들은 이미 여기에 있습니다.
Isn't it that way?
그렇지 않나요?
- Dad! - Yeah!
- 아빠! - 응!
Congratulations! You were incredible.
축하해요! 당신은 정말 대단했어요.
I thought you were going to break the drums.
나는 당신이 드럼을 부러뜨릴 것이라고 생각했습니다.
you seem
당신은 보인다
a member of Aerosmith.
에어로스미스의 회원입니다.
No!
아니요!
I wasn't so good.
나는 별로 좋지 않았다.
He's sweating.
그는 땀을 흘리고 있습니다.
Daniel!
다니엘!
Mother!
어머니!
When did you arrive?
언제 도착하셨나요?
I arrived yesterday.
나는 어제 도착했다.
So long.
그럼 또.
Yes.
예.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I've heard a lot about you.
나는 당신에 대해 많이 들었습니다.